+44 (0) 7506-583-276 chris@chrisedwardsdesign.com linkedin.com/in/chris-edwards-b97488276 Chris Edwards multi-disciplinary designer chrisedwardsdesign.com

BACKGROUND

I'm a multidisciplinary designer with a strong focus in User Interface Design and Digital Design. My skill set also includes a good foundation in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Shopify Liquid. Additionally, I have some experience and a keen interest in Motion Design with both 2d and 3D, using software packages such as Adobe After Effects, Blender and Cinema 4D. My portfolio spans diverse industries, including fashion and e-commerce.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Graphic Designer / Chris Edwards Design (Apr – present)

- Delivering creative and high-quality design solutions to a diverse range of clients.
- Utilising industry-standard design tools and technologies to create visually appealing and user-centred creative across various digital platforms.
- Proven track record of successfully managing multiple projects simultaneously, meeting deadlines and exceeding client expectations.

Junior Frontend Developer · UX Designer / Digital Media Team Ltd. (Oct 2022 – Mar 2023)

- UX design, wire-framing, prototyping, and usability testing of client Shopify websites.
- Assisting in conducting audits of Shopify websites to identify areas for improvement in performance, accessibility, code quality and conversion rate optimisation.
- · Writing efficient, clean and maintainable HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Shopify Liquid code.
- Staying updated with industry trends and best practices in frontend development.
- · Conducting testing and debugging to identify and fix issues or bugs.

Digital Designer / Good For Nothing Clothing Ltd. (Jan 2018 – Oct 2022)

- · Overseeing the development and maintenance of the company website.
- · Designing and implementing front-end design elements to enhance user experience.
- Collaborate closely with in-house menswear designer to ensure a cohesive brand aesthetic across all platforms.
- Design and creative for branding, packaging, marketing, email, social and digital ads.
- Support for video post-production including editing and animated motion graphics.
- Assisted with the creative and logistical planning of photo and video shoots.

Graphic Design Internship / Primary Engineer (Mar 2017 – Nov 2017)

- Design for educational documentation as well as video editing with animation to showcase student inventions.
- Creative support for student shows, contributing to the successful execution of exhibitions by assisting with mounting and displaying artworks.

Junior Freelance Graphic Designer / Contract: MMS Media Ltd. (in-house: Jul 2015 – Oct 2015)

· Design for event nights in and around Manchester including posters, flyers, banners and social content.

Junior Freelance Graphic Designer / Ground Control Productions (in-house: Jan 2015 – Oct 2015)

- · Parklife Artist liaison festival wristbands, lanyards, tokens and printed ephemera.
- · Company business cards and infographics.

Design Team Assistant / Ear To The Ground (unpaid work experience: May 2014 – Mar 2015)

- · Assisting with presentations, case studies and design asset management.
- Digital Storyboarding with CAD mockups and infographics.

EDUCATION

Manchester Metropolitan University (Sept 2006 – Jul 2009) Bachelor of Arts (B.A Hons) Degree: Illustration with Animation

SOFTWARE

Proficient:

InDesign · Illustrator · Photoshop · Figma · XD · After Effects · Shopify

Good Foundation:

Visual Studio Code $\,\cdot\,\,$ Cinema 4D $\,\cdot\,\,$ Blender $\,\cdot\,\,$ Klaviyo $\,\cdot\,\,$ Processing $\,\cdot\,\,$ Office 365

CODE

Good Foundation:

HTML · CSS · Javascript · Shopify Liquid

STRENGTHS

User Interface Design, Typography and Motion design. I'm also excited by the opportunity to learn and experiment with new technologies wherever possible. My strengths lie in creating visually appealing and intuitive creatives that incorporate both form and functionality, with a goal to produce designs that capture attention and enhance user engagement.